Data module code

Description: The element <dmCode> contains the data module code and forms part of the
unique identifier of a data module. All data modules are allocated a data module code.
The data module code provides four top-level pieces of information:
- The identification of the Product, or part of the Product, about which the data module has
been written, using the model identifier, the system difference code, the standard
numbering system, the disassembly code and the disassembly code variant
- The identification of the information type, using the information code and the information
code variant
- The identification of the location at which the information in the data module is appropriate,
using the item location code
- The identification of the type of learning content in learning data modules. Refer to
Chap 4.3.
Establishing the data module code requires a data module coding strategy. Refer to Chap 4.3.

Child elements:
- None


Markup element: <dmCode>

Attributes:
- modelIdentCode (M), the model identifier or project name. Refer to Chap 4.3.1.
- systemDiffCode (M), the system difference code. Refer to Chap 4.3.2.
- systemCode (M), the system code (part of the SNS). Refer to Chap 4.3.3.
- subSystemCode (M), the subsystem code (part of the SNS). Refer to Chap 4.3.3.
- subSubSystemCode (M), the sub-subsystem code (part of the SNS). Refer to
Chap 4.3.3.
- assyCode (M), the assembly code (part of the SNS). Refer to Chap 4.3.3.
- disassyCode (M), the disassembly code. Refer to Chap 3.8 and Chap 4.3.4.
- disassyCodeVariant (M), the disassembly code variant. Refer to Chap 4.3.5.
- infoCode (M), the information code. Refer to Chap 4.3.6.
- infoCodeVariant (M), the information code variant. Refer to Chap 4.3.7.
- itemLocationCode (M), the item location code. Refer to Chap 4.3.8.
- learnCode (O), the learn code. Refer to Chap 4.3.9 and Chap 8.5.
- learnEventCode (O), the learn event code. Refer to Chap 3.9.5.2.13 and
Chap 4.3.10


Markup example for maintenance data modules:

<dmCode modelIdentCode="S1000DBIKE" systemDiffCode="AAA"
systemCode="DA2" subSystemCode="0" subSubSystemCode="0"
assyCode="00" disassyCode="00" disassyCodeVariant="AA"
infoCode="041" infoCodeVariant="A" itemLocationCode="A"/>


Markup example for training data modules:

<dmCode modelIdentCode="S1000DBIKE" systemDiffCode="AAA"
systemCode="DA2" subSystemCode="0" subSubSystemCode="0"
assyCode="00" disassyCode="00" disassyCodeVariant="AA"
infoCode="041" infoCodeVariant="A" itemLocationCode="A"
learnCode="T12" learnEventCode="C"/>

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  
Language

Description: The element <language> is used to describe the language in which the data
module is written.


Markup element: <language>

Attributes:
- languageIsoCode (M), the two alpha characters from International Standards
Organization (ISO) 639. Simplified languages are coded by using additional codes similar
to, and not in conflict with, ISO 639 codes. For example, languageIsoCode="sx"
means a Simplified Technical English® (ASD-STE100) data module and 
languageIsoCode="ra" means a rationalized French data module.
- countryIsoCode (M), the two alpha characters from ISO 3166 to denote the country
where the language is spoken

Child elements:
- None


Markup examples:

The following example is for a data module written in the default language:
<language languageIsoCode="sx" countryIsoCode="US"/>

The following example is for a data module written in Simplified Technical English with Oxford
English spelling:
<language languageIsoCode="sx" countryIsoCode="GB"/>

The following example is for a data module written in French:
<language languageIsoCode="fr" countryIsoCode="FR"/>

The following example is for a data module written in German:
<language languageIsoCode="de" countryIsoCode="DE"/>


The following example is for a data module written in German for an Austrian end user:
<language languageIsoCode="de" countryIsoCode="AT"/>

